ANDRÉ AUSTVOLL

UX designer & researcher

+47 40408106

a.austvoll@gmail.com

Oslo, Norway

Pf aaustvoll.myportfolio.com

n linkedin.com/in/andre-austvoll/

EDUCATION

Certificate, *UX Design Immersion*CareerFoundry, 2020 - 2021

Master of Arts (MA), Somatic studies & Laban movement analysis Univ of Surrey 2003 - 2005

SKILLS

- UX/UI design
- Storyboarding & sketching
- Design Thinking
- User Journeys
- User & Competitor Research
- Persona Creation
- Information Architecture
- Wireframing and Prototyping
- Usability Testing
- Design Presentations

SOFTWARE

- Adobe XD
- Figma
- Sketch
- Premiere Pro
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Mamut Business
- Marvel
- Unity 3D

LANGUAGES

- Norwegian
- English
- German
- French

PROFILE

I am a UX designer specialised in immersive media like Virtual and Augmented Reality. I love to solve usability problems and create data driven and user centred web applications, apps and spatial simulations. Currently I am consulting on professional solutions for VR, video for streaming, videochat and retail.

EXPERIENCE

VIDEOUTSTYR NORGE AS Oslo 2011 - Present

Advised on a large number of video, immersive media and communications projects for clients in broadcast and video production, government, education, industry, medical and law enforcement.

- Product manager for Virtual Reality and 360 video
- Optimised storage system to ease logistics and in-house UX.
- Responsibilities included SoMe, sales and technical support for professional video hardware and software.
- Redesigned UX/UI of webshop for custom microphone windscreens. The result was an automated order flow that eliminated several steps and expedited sales.

Achievement: A marine farming visitor centre needed a way to show what goes on under the sea surface. I led the development of a 360 underwater surveillance solution that opened up a new market segment for the company.

MICRODANCE Oslo 2001 - 2011

I started and ran my own business, working as a dancer, instructor, choreographer, researcher and video producer. Working in the creative field has refined my ability to resolve objectives on time and within financial requirements, while completing projects to a high standard.

- Managed projects and took responsibility for art direction, planning, budgeting, executing projects and evaluating team efforts.
- Project locations: Brazil, China, Finland, Norway, Poland, Russia, Slovenia, England, USA.

CANON Oslo & South Norway 2009 - 2011

I acted as customer and dealer contact with responsibility for customer success and marketing of cameras and photographic printers. I enjoyed figuring out my clients needs and supporting them in purchase decisions.

- Evaluating user pain points and goals for professional video equipment
- On-site follow-up of resellers around mid and south Norway.
- Product management, field demonstrations, documentation of shop displays and acquiring user feedback.